HELEN ADAKU CHINEDU

HOUSE 25, JULIUS BERGER STAFF QUARTERS, KARMO, ABUJA

E-mail:helenchinedu26@gmail.com

Mobile: 09059682563, 08135563606

PROFILE

I hold a Bachelor of Science and Education in Chemistry Education with masters in Chemistry Education. (in View). I have over four years Basic Science teaching experience of both the Nigerian and British curricula in Primary and Secondary schools. With a great passion for knowledge acquisition and impartation; I seek constantly to build young minds by directing students towards the discovery as well as full realisation of their potentials, talents and aspirations in the course of my teaching career. I am a highly efficient, reliable and honest person who contributes passionately through resourcefulness and innovation towards the achievement of the organizational goals of whichever establishment I work for. Notably characteristic of my personality are excellent interpersonal and computer science skills as well as written and verbal communication.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

DATE

Karryfield International School, Utako, Abuja. November, 2019 Till Date

Grade 3 Teacher

§ Instruct pupils in Basic Science using hands-on learning experiences

§ Prepare lesson plans using the British/Nigerian curriculum

§ Organise the classroom and learning resources

§ Create displays to encourage a positive learning environment

Ausphine International School, Kugbo, Abuja

November, 2019 - September, 2018

Grade 3 Teacher

- § Lead students in activities to promote their physical, mental and social development and their school readiness.
- § Assigned and corrected homework.
- § Prepared, administered and corrected tests.
- § Evaluated the progress of students and discussed results with students, parents and school officials.

Odo-Otin Secondary School, Odo-Otin, Osun State

June, 2013 – July, 2012

NYSC Student Chemistry Teacher

- **§** Determined individual needs of students
- § Discussed results with parents and school officials.
- § Prepared and implemented remedial programs for students requiring extra help.
- § Participated in staff meetings, educational conferences and teacher training workshops.

Whiteplains British School, Jabi, Abuja

Teaching Practice

June, 2011 - January, 2011

- § Understudied the head teacher in charge of chemistry.
- § Organised science laboratory equipment for practical classes.
- § Helped the weak students to catch up with topics they had difficulty in.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

§ University of Lagos, Lagos.

M.ed Chemistry Education

(In View)

§ University of Abuja, Abuja.

B.sc (ed) Chemistry Education

2008-2011

§ Regina Pacis College, Garki 2, Abuja.

West African Senior School Certificate Examination

2016

§ Millenium Training Acquisition Limited, Osogbo, Osun State

November, 2013

Health Safety and Environment (HSE level 2).

§ Teachers Registration Council of Nigeria -

June, 2013

Certificate of Registration (CT/R/07748).

§ Odilux Global Link Limited, Eagle Island, Port Harcourt -

August, 2009

Diploma in Computer Proficiency.

HOBBIES

Reading, Journaling, Exploring, Information Technology